Hey, she's not as pretty as she was
她不像她29歲時那麼漂亮
when she was 29.
Miss Green would like to establish some ground
在葛林小姐出來之前 她要先把幾件事說清楚
rules before she comes out.
She would appreciate it if you didn't use
如果你發現你變31歲了 你會怎麼感覺？
the words old or downhill or they still
她希望你們不要用到如「老」 或者「走下坡」等字眼…
look pretty damn good.
或是「它們看來還是很棒」
They do.
它們還是
Rachel, come on out.
瑞秋，出來
Monica made breakfast.
摩妮卡做了早餐
Chocolate chip pancakes.
巧克力碎片鬆餅
We've got presents.
我們有禮物給你
Good ones?
好的禮物？
They all came from the list you handed
都是兩星期前你給的單子上的
out to us two weeks ago.
Well, can I keep the presents and still
我可以只收禮物 而仍然是29歲嗎？
be 29?
Come on, Rach.
瑞秋，30歲沒什麼大不了
Look, turn it this way.
我今天滿30歲了
30 is not that big a deal.
瑞秋，30歲沒什麼大不了
Oh, really?
哦，對了
Is that how you felt when you turned
真的？你滿30時也是這麼覺得嗎？
30?
有點緊張
Why, God, why?
為什麼，上帝，為什麼？
We had a deal.
我們講好的了 讓其他人變老，我不要！
Let the others grow old, not me.
You know, I'm still 29 in Guam.
Hey, 30 is not that old.
瑞秋，30歲沒什麼大不了
Do you know how old the Earth is?
你做的對
Late 30s?
Oh, come on, you guys.
-來 -好了
Is it just me?
只有我這樣嗎？是我反應過度嗎？
Am I overreacting to this?
No, Rach.
該死的！
It's not just you.
不，不是只有你 我的30歲生日也不好過
My 30th birthday certainly wasn't that much fun.
And now Chandler.
現在是錢德了！
We're all getting so old.
我們都變得這麼老
Why are you doing this to us?
你為什麼這樣對我們？
Rach, you're in a great place in your
你的生活過得很好 你有很棒的工作，很好的朋友
life.
抬起來…
I mean, come on.
瑞秋，別這樣
You have an amazing job.
你的生活過得很好 你有很棒的工作，很好的朋友
Good friends.
Yeah.
是啊
Your roommate's a soap opera star.
你的室友是連續劇明星
Your character's in a coma.
你的角色在昏迷中
I promised myself I wasn't going to cry
我答應自己這個生日一定不哭
at this one.
Look, you know, I know my life's going
我知道你經歷的
pretty well, but I look around and I
just see so many people who've accomplished so
many of their goals by the time they're
在30歲以前 就完成了他們的目標
30.
有點緊張
Yeah, but you shouldn't compare yourself to me.
是啊，你不應該和我比
Come on.
瑞秋，別這樣
OK, come on, baby.
Let's do it, baby.
我們談談
Come on.
瑞秋，別這樣
There you go.
-來 -好了
Come on.
瑞秋，別這樣
Yes, yes, yes.
-是的！是的！ -不
I did it.
我成功了！在跳跳球上走了一里
One mile on a hippity hop.
That's it.
什麼事？
That's everything I wanted to do before I
30歲前我想完成的事
was 30.
Oh, except I wanted to patch things up
除了我想和我妹修好關係
with my sister.
Oh, well.
嗯，可是
But yeah.
And girls, this thing is a godsend.
女人，這東西是上帝給的禮物 如果你懂我的意思
If you know what I mean.
30.
有點緊張
Oh, I mean 30.
-老天 -怎麼？
Monica, you remember mean old Mrs. Krieger in
the 5th grade?
She was 30.
Let's have some fun, huh?
來做點有趣的事吧，你想做什麼？
What do you want to do today?
Nothing.
什麼也不做，我什麼也不想做
I don't want to do anything.
Yeah, doing nothing on your 30th is better
在30歲生日時什麼都不做 總比做笨事好，像羅斯一樣
than doing something stupid, like Ross.
Hey, that was a practical purchase.
那是很實際的一項購買
I needed that car for transportation.
我需要那車子做交通工具
OK?
好
I have a child.
好嗎？我有小孩
How hot do I look in this, huh?
我在這車裡看來很拉風吧？
Ross, a sports car?
羅斯，一台跑車？
Wouldn't it be cheaper to just stuff a
在褲子裡塞襪子不是比較便宜？
sock down there?
That's not what this is about, OK?
這不是為了那個
I am a sports car enthusiast.
我是跑車熱愛者
I've always been into cars.
-我一直都很喜歡車 -它的馬力多少？
Hey, what's the horsepower on this thing?
I don't know, but look how shiny.
不知道，你看它多亮呀！
I can't believe you bought this.
-你竟然買了這台車 -帥哥，載我一程吧？
Really?
真的？你滿30時也是這麼覺得嗎？
God, Ross, what were you thinking?
-來 -好了
I know it's really shallow, but a part
記住，這是一個驚喜
of me wants him again.
Oh, well, get in line, missy.
嗯，可是
So, can I have a ride, stud?
-你竟然買了這台車 -帥哥，載我一程吧？
Hop in.
跳上車
Get ready for the smoothest ride of your
準備好你這輩子最穩的一程
life.
抬起來…
Damn it!
可惡
OK, who's next?
好了，下一個是誰？
You know what?
女人，這東西是上帝給的禮物 如果你懂我的意思
I am going to do something today.
我要在身上打個洞
I'm not just going to sit around like
今天我一定要做點什麼 我不要像老太太一樣閒坐在這兒
some old lady.
I'm going to get something pierced.
我要在身上打個洞
Like my nose or my tongue or something.
像是鼻子、舌頭，或是別的地方
Really?
真的？你滿30時也是這麼覺得嗎？
Because, you know, that hurts.
真的？那會痛的
So what?
那又怎麼？我是這麼想…
You know what, the way I see it...
Ow!
Son of a bitch!
該死的！
Look, Rachel, I know what you're going through.
我知道你經歷的
I'm totally freaked out about turning 25.
我25歲生日時嚇壞了
Get out of my apartment.
離開我家
Rachel, for what it's worth, I think that
you're doing great.
瑞秋，你做的很好
I mean, you know, let's face it, no
你愛怎麼看都行，已經在發生了
one handles this well.
正視事實吧，沒有人能真的 好好處理這件事
At least of all you.
至少你不行
Why?
嘿…
What'd you do?
怎麼回事？
Weren't you asked to leave, Sonny?
Oh, would you put that back on?
嘿，你開門了！
Monica's going to be here any minute.
放回去，摩妮卡隨時會到家
But it hurts my Joey's apple.
可是喬伊的蘋果會痛
OK, for the last time, it's not named
告訴你最後一次 它不是以每一個人的名字命名的
after each individual man.
You've done a wonderful job with this party,
錢德，你把宴會辦得真好 每樣東西都很美麗
Chandler.
現在是錢德了！
Everything looks so lovely.
Oh, well, not as lovely as you.
沒有像你這麼美麗
I mean, I can't believe it.
真不能相信，真不公平！
I can't believe that you would have a
不能相信你有位30歲的女兒
30-year-old daughter.
And you, I can't believe that you would
不能相信你有件30歲的燕尾服
have a tux that's 30 years old.
It's older than that.
這比30年還老 羅斯是在這件燕尾服旁有的
Ross was actually conceived right near this tuxedo.
Oh.
Wait, everybody, hide, hide.
大家躲起來！我看到她了，她來了
I saw her, she's coming.
OK, OK, everybody down.
大家蹲下！
Everybody down.
Crap.
OK, everybody stay here.
好，大家都清楚了？
I will find out what's going on.
怎麼回事？
Hey, you got a tux.
嘿，你開門了！
Hey, are you drunk?
嘿，你喝醉了嗎？
No.
沒有
OK.
好
See, I was a little nervous about turning...
我對要滿30歲…
30.
有點緊張
So the buzz boys took me out for
收碗的小弟帶我去喝酒
some drinks.
I want to puke on you later.
待會可能會吐在你身上
OK, here's the thing.
你做的對
We have thrown a very formal surprise party
驚喜！
for you in there.
不要到街上！
All your friends are in there and your
-你的朋友和父母都在裡面 -不！
parents.
Yes.
記得
No.
沒有
Oh, no, my parents have never seen me
哦，不！我父母從沒看我醉過
drunk.
我醉了！
That they know of.
就他們所知
Here's the thing.
事情是這樣的 我們替你辦了一個驚喜宴會
We're going to get you some coffee and
我要在身上打個洞
they will never know that you're drunk.
你醉了
Really, you promise?
Yes, I'll take care of it.
-你確定？ -我會處理好的
I love you so much.
我好愛你
OK, we have to do something about your
好了，要對你的口臭想想辦法
breath.
What about your breath?
那你的呢？
That's still yours.
那還是你的口臭
OK, now remember, it's a surprise party.
記住，這是一個驚喜
So when you go in, act surprised.
你進去時要顯得很驚訝
Ready?
好了嗎？
Surprise!
驚喜！
OK, forward.
好，前進，前進
Forward, stop.
好，前…停！
OK, back, stop.
好，退後…停！
OK.
好
Stop, stop, stop.
停！停！
Ross, just forget about it.
羅斯，一台跑車？
The guy's got you totally wedged in.
Is this yours?
那還是你的口臭
No, no, it's mine.
不，羅斯，不，有問題
It's mine.
很好啊
Dude, you so need this car.
你為什麼這樣對我們？
OK, OK, here's what we're going to do,
好，我們這麼做
OK?
好
I'm going to break into this minivan.
我打開這台休旅車車門 將它放在空檔
Put it in neutral.
You guys push it forward so Ross can
你們把它向前推，羅斯就能開出來了
drive out of the spot.
離開我家
OK?
好
OK.
All right, here we go.
好，來吧
Happy 30th birthday.
30歲生日快樂！來
Here.
是菲比
It's for the child in you.
給你裡面的孩子，還有女子
And the woman.
Happy 30th.
30歲快樂！
Right, why do you keep saying that?
你為什麼一直這麼說？
Because it's our 30th birthday.
因為這是我們的30歲生日
Yeah, no, we're not 30, we're 31.
對，我們不是30，我們是31
OK.
好
Wait.
等一下
Oh, it's you.
哦，是你
Yeah.
是啊
What?
等一下
Yeah, we're not 30, we're 31.
對，我們不是30，我們是31
Nuh-uh.
Uh-huh.
That's what it says on my birth certificate.
我的出生證明上是這麼寫的
You have your birth certificate?
你有出生證明？
Yeah, I got a big box of family
我媽去世時，我拿到了 一箱子家庭文件
stuff when my mom died.
Our mom.
我們的媽
Right, OK.
好，好
Do you have my birth certificate?
你有出生證明？
No, I sold it to a Swedish runaway.
-你有我的嗎？ -沒有，我賣給了一個逃家的瑞典人
Oh, my God.
我的老天
Oh, my God, we are 31.
我的老天，我們31了！
Yeah.
是啊
I just lost a whole year of my
我失去了整整一年生命
life.
抬起來…
OK.
好
Your middle name is Pamela?
-你的中間名字是潘蜜拉？ -對
Yes.
記得
I never knew mine.
我從不知道我的是什麼 你記得是什麼嗎？
Do you remember what it is?
Yes.
記得
Phoebe.
是菲比
That's my first name.
-那是我的正式名字 -對，好吧，那我不知道
Right, OK.
好，好
Then no.
-那是我的正式名字 -對，好吧，那我不知道
Look at that, we made it all the
不，不，只是一個玩笑
way across the room.
我們成功地穿過了客廳 你做的很好
You're doing great.
瑞秋，你做的很好
What's going on?
怎麼回事？
Monica's a little drunk.
摩妮卡有一點醉了
Yay, I love drunk Monica.
我喜歡酒醉的摩妮卡
Oh, she's so much more fun than regular
她比正常的摩妮卡有趣多了
Monica.
摩妮卡做了早餐
She doesn't want her parents to know she's
她不想讓她的父母知道
drunk.
我醉了！
Oh, all right, all right.
好極了！
Here's what we'll do.
好，好，我們這麼做
I'll get twice as drunk as Monica, and
我來比她醉得厲害兩倍 就沒有人會注意她了
then no one's even going to notice her.
Drunk Phoebe's mean.
是菲比
OK, you watch your tone with me.
What's going on?
怎麼回事？
Monica's wasted.
摩妮卡醉了
Maybe that'll liven up this party.
或許能讓這個宴會有點生機
Can't we just go help her get changed,
你能不能幫她換衣服？
please?
她希望你們不要用到如「老」 或者「走下坡」等字眼…
OK, but taking care of a drunk naked
照顧酒醉，裸體的女人 好像是喬伊的工作
woman seems like a job for Joey.
Yeah.
是啊
This one's from me.
這是我的禮物
It wasn't on your list, but hopefully you'll
這不在你的禮物單子上 不過它真的很好玩
think it's really fun.
很好啊
A scooter.
滑板車
Stick to the list.
照著單子買
Always stick to the list.
永遠記得照著單子買
Oh, no, no, I love it, thank you.
不，不，我很喜歡，謝謝
OK, open ours next, open ours next.
下一個開我們的禮物！ 下一個開我們的！
OK.
好
Now that you're a couple, we don't get
你們現在是一對 我們就沒兩個禮物了？
two presents from you guys?
For my last birthday, you gave me a
我上一個生日，你送我一個擁抱
hug.
OK, read the card, read the card.
念卡片！念卡片！
OK.
好
Happy birthday, Grandma.
生日快樂，祖母
Over the hill.
開始走下坡總比…
Then buried under it.
被埋在坡下要好
Oh, I love Monica Chandler, that's funny.
我們愛你，摩妮卡和錢德 好好笑
Oh, no, no, no, no, no, no, no,
no, that was a joke.
不，不，只是一個玩笑
No, I know, I get it, it's funny.
我知道，我懂了，很好笑
No, because you're not a grandmother.
因為你不是祖母
No, I know, because to be a grandmother,
you have to be married and have children,
做為一個祖母，必須結了婚有小孩
and I don't have any of those things.
我全都沒有，所以真的很好笑
That's why it's so funny.
I'm just gonna go.
我要…
All you had to do was buy the
你只需要買張卡片而己
card.
Hey, look who's back, it's the birthday girl.
演講，演講！壽星演講
How's the birthday girl feeling?
30歲生日快樂！來
Well, I feel fine, but I think you're
不，不，我很喜歡，謝謝
bumming out the rest of the kids.
我想生三個小孩
What?
等一下
OK, you know what?
-老天 -怎麼？
I realize it was stupid to get upset
為著沒有先生孩子就不高興，是很笨
about not having a husband and kids.
All I really needed was a plan.
我只需要一個計劃
See, I want to have three kids.
我想生三個小孩
Well, let me guess, and you want to
來做點有趣的事吧，你想做什麼？
have them all at the same time, and
你要全部同一個時候生 把他們給你弟弟
you want to have them for your brother.
As I was saying, I should probably have
我正在說…
the first of the three kids by the
我想生三個小孩
time I'm 35, right?
Which gives me five years.
這樣我還有五年
I love this plan, I want to marry
什麼也不做，我什麼也不想做
this plan.
我的計劃很有效
You could do that, I'd marry the hippity
知道我真的很想說什麼嗎？
hop.
跳上車
So if I want to have a kid
我想生三個小孩
when I'm 35, I don't have to get
如果我35時要生孩子 我34歲時才需要懷孕
pregnant until I'm 34, which gives Prada four
years to start making maternity clothes.
Prada還有四年時間生產孕婦裝
Oh, wait, but...
哦，是你
Now, I do want to be married for
什麼也不做，我什麼也不想做
a year before I get pregnant.
我想在懷孕之前至少結婚一年
Really?
真的？你滿30時也是這麼覺得嗎？
That long?
真的？要那麼久？
Look all you want, it's happening.
你愛怎麼看都行，已經在發生了
Now, so I don't have to get married
我到33歲再結婚就好，我還有3年
until I'm 33.
That's three years, that's three whole years.
我到33歲再結婚就好，我還有3年
Oh, wait a minute, though.
不過，等一下
I'll need a year and a half to
我需要一年半來籌備婚禮
plan the wedding.
And I'd like to know the guy for
我希望能認識這個人一年至一年半…
like a year, year and a half before
we get engaged, which means I need to
meet the guy by the time I'm 30.
這表示我必須在30歲時認識這個人
Which is fine, because you just turned 28!
沒有問題，因為你才剛剛滿…
No, Ross, no, it is not fine.
不，羅斯，不，有問題
According to my plan, I should already be
with the guy that I'm gonna marry.
我應該和我要嫁的對象在一起了
Whoo-hoo!
Oh, you quit hogging it!
你可不可以不要跳？
Oh, I'm telling you, it's like watching Bambi
我告訴你，這就好像看著斑比學走路
learn how to walk.
You're drunk.
你醉了
Mom and Dad are gonna be mad.
爸和媽會生氣
Maybe I'm a little drunk.
也許我有一點醉了
Hey, are those crab cakes?
那是蟹餅嗎？
Did I not tell you to come straight
我不是告訴你 蟹餅一出來立刻拿來給我？
to me when more crab cakes were ready?
那是蟹餅嗎？
How are you feeling?
覺得怎麼樣？
You are so handsome.
你好帥
I wanna make love to you right here,
我想在此時此地和你上床
right now.
I really wish that you wouldn't.
我希望你不會
Now, all you have to do is just
你只需要買張卡片而己
get through a little bit more, okay?
再撐一下，我們就可以帶你去睡覺
Then we can put you in bed, okay?
Just smile, and don't talk to anyone.
只要微笑，不要說話
Speech!
演講，演講！壽星演講
Let's hear from the birthday girl, huh?
Don't you see?
覺得怎麼樣？
Everybody's looking at me.
看，大家都在看我
The plan's working.
我的計劃很有效
I didn't even have to take off my
我還沒脫掉上衣呢
top yet.
Speech!
演講，演講！壽星演講
Come on, Mom.
瑞秋，出來
Speech!
演講，演講！壽星演講
Hey, Chandler, you can't keep your hands off
你連離開她一秒鐘都不行
her for one second.
Oh, I think it's nice.
很好啊
I think it's necessary.
我必須這樣
I wanna thank you all for coming.
我要謝謝大家來到這裡
My family and my friends.
我的家人和…
Speech!
演講，演講！壽星演講
I'd really like to say that I'm, um...
我很想說我…
You know what I'd really like to say?
知道我真的很想說什麼嗎？
I'm drunk!
我醉了！
That's right, Mom, is hammered!
沒錯，爸，媽
More!
And I've smoked a cigarette.
我抽過煙
And I've got a box of ding-dongs
hidden in my underwear drawer.
It's all okay.
沒關係，沒關係，因為…
It's okay, because I turned 30 today.
我今天滿30歲了
And I can do anything I want.
我想做什麼就做什麼
Because I am a grown-up.
因為我是成年人了
Okay, quick, help me get this off.
好，快，替我脫掉
Yeah.
是啊
I lost a whole year.
我失去了整整一年
I can't believe it.
真不能相信，真不公平！
This is so unfair.
Come on, Pheebs, it'll be okay.
菲比，沒有關係的
Will it?
是嗎？是嗎？
How would you feel if you found out
如果你發現你變31歲了 你會怎麼感覺？
you were 31?
That's not gonna happen.
不會的，因為我們有個新約定
No, because we have a new deal.
Plus, it totally ruined my schedule.
還有，這毀了我的時間表
I...
I haven't done any of the things I
我還沒做那些我31歲前想做的事
wanted to do by the time I was
我想做什麼就做什麼
31.
Like what?
-像什麼？ -像是我還不認識任何葡萄牙人
Like, okay, I...
好，好
I...
I haven't met any Portuguese people.
-像什麼？ -像是我還不認識任何葡萄牙人
I...
I haven't had the perfect kiss.
我還沒有完美地接吻過
And I haven't been to sniper school.
我還沒去上狙擊手學校
Baby, you know what?
你為什麼一直這麼說？
Why don't we just go upstairs and have
我們去吃蛋糕吧
some birthday cake?
No, I just feel like being by myself
我只想一個人靜一下，待會見，謝謝
for a while.
-老天 -怎麼？
All right, I'll see you guys later.
好極了！
Thanks.
我只想一個人靜一下，待會見，謝謝
Oh, poor Pheebs.
可憐的菲比
Hey, you know what, you guys?
知道我真的很想說什麼嗎？
I think I'm gonna go walk her home.
嘿，知道嗎？我想我要陪她走回家
Oh, man.
-老天 -怎麼？
What?
等一下
He's gonna eat the cake.
他會吃了蛋糕
Pheebs, get up.
是菲比
Listen, uh...
聽著，我…
Close your eyes.
閉上眼睛
If that's one thing you can cross off
你可以將這一項從單子上劃掉
your list.
這不在你的禮物單子上 不過它真的很好玩
Oh, yeah.
哦，對了
Oh, and plus, I'm 1 16th Portuguese.
還有，我是16分之1的葡萄牙人
Okay, is everybody clear?
好，大家都清楚了？
We're gonna pick it up...
我們要將它抬起來…
And move it.
然後移動它
All we need is teamwork, okay?
只需要團隊工作 我們要抬起這台車…
We're gonna lift the car...
And slide it out.
把它滑出來
Lift...
抬起來…
And slide.
滑出來
Ross, I really don't think...
-羅斯，我真的不覺得這… -抬起來…
Lift...
抬起來…
And slide.
滑出來
All right.
好極了！
Come on, dogs.
-來 -好了
Let's lift this sucker.
他會吃了蛋糕
Oh, unless you're scared.
因為你不是祖母
Oh, little weakling scared.
你們的小口琴醉了
Good teamwork.
好的禮物？
Okay, here we go.
-好，開始吧 -好，大夥兒
All right, everyone.
Lift...
抬起來…
And slide.
滑出來
Well, come on, Rach.
演講，演講！
My turn just started.
-嘿，喬伊… -別這樣，瑞秋，才剛輪到我
Actually, I just want to talk to Ted.
其實我是要和泰格說話
Oh, okay.
哦，好，嘿，我可以到外面溜嗎？
Hey.
嘿…
Can I ride this outside?
哦，好，嘿，我可以到外面溜嗎？
Whatever, okay?
好，好
I'm not your mother.
隨便，我不是你媽
Okay.
好
Not in the street, Brooklyn!
不要到街上！
Hey.
嘿…
How you doing?
覺得怎麼樣？
Are you feeling any better?
-有沒有覺得好一點？ -有，我很好，我…
Yeah, I'm doing okay.
I'm...
Um...
Let's talk.
我們談談
Okay.
好
Um...
What's up?
什麼事？
Oh, Ted, um...
哦，是你
You're such a great guy.
你真是個好男人，我們在一起很開心
And we have so much fun together.
But I...
-可是我… -等一下
Wait.
等一下
I think I see where you're going.
我想我知道你要做什麼
But before you say anything else, can I
在你說任何話之前 我可以先說一件事嗎？
just say one more thing?
Well said.
說的好
And a good example of the fun I
正是我所謂很開心的好例子
was referring to.
Uh, but...
I just think I'm past the point where
但我想我已經過了只要開心的時候
I can, you know, just have fun.
不知道，你看它多亮呀！
Rachel, don't do this.
-羅斯，我真的不覺得這… -抬起來…
This is just because you're turning 30.
瑞秋，不要這樣 這只是因為你30歲了
Yeah, it is.
是的
But you're just a kid.
而你只是個孩子，你才25歲
I mean, you're...
You're 25.
而你只是個孩子，你才25歲
24, actually.
Oh, God.
-其實是24歲 -老天
You know what I wish?
你知道我希望什麼？ 我希望你比現在大6歲
I wish you were six years older.
Well, actually, if I'm wishing for stuff, I
如果是希望的話 其實我希望自己年輕6歲
actually wish I was six years younger.
Me too.
-我也是 -是啊，對不起
Yeah, sorry.
Sorry.
Hey, let it go.
嘿，談得怎麼樣？
Oh.
If I only want two kids, can I
如果我只要生兩個孩子 我可以再保留他一年嗎？
keep him for another year?
You did the right thing.
你做的對
I don't like this anymore.
我不喜歡它了
Well, here we are.
我們在這兒，一群30歲的人
Just a bunch of 30-year-olds.
Wow, do you realize in 10 years, we're
你知道再過10年 我們就40歲了？
gonna be 40?
Why, God?
為什麼，上帝？
Why are you doing this to us?
你為什麼這樣對我們？
Yes!
記得
My baby's finally free!
太好了！我的寶貝終於自由了
Right.
好極了！
Start it up.
啟動，我們走！
Let's go.
Woo-hoo!
How hot are we?
我們拉不拉風？
Hmm?
You wanna buy a car?
你要買車嗎？
No.
沒有